<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading Every Presidential Biography on Mathias Kools</title>
    <link>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading Every Presidential Biography on Mathias Kools</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Jackson</title>
      <link>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/7_andrew_jackson.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/7_andrew_jackson.html</guid>
      <description>Andrew Jackson On Andrew Jackson I read Teri Kanefield&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Andrew Jackson: The Making of America #2&amp;rdquo;.
I found this book quite short. That might be why it&amp;rsquo;s marked for &amp;ldquo;middle school&amp;rdquo; readers0. It may also be for the reason that Andrew Jackson was not as literate and grammatical and prolific as presidents of the past. So maybe there&amp;rsquo;s not a &amp;ldquo;John Adams Journal&amp;rdquo; to dump into the pages (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you McCullough).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Quincy Adams</title>
      <link>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/6_john_quincy_adams.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/6_john_quincy_adams.html</guid>
      <description>John Quincy Adams On John Quincy Adams I read Fred Kaplan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;John Quincy Adams: American Visionary&amp;rdquo;.
Much like his father John Quincy Adams kept a journal to capture the major and minute details of his life. Much like McCullough, Kaplan doesn&amp;rsquo;t spare any of this writing from the reader. This was a slog to get through. But I come out the other end feeling like I really know John Quincy Adams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Monroe</title>
      <link>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/5_james_monroe.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/5_james_monroe.html</guid>
      <description>James Monroe On James Monroe I read Tim McGrath&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;James Monroe: A Life&amp;rdquo;.
I read this book a while ago. And my memory isn&amp;rsquo;t so good.
I do remember the author doing a wonderful job capturing the magic of James Monroe&amp;rsquo;s tours of the United States. McGrath convinced me this was a president who cared for unity and pragmatic decisions. That Monroe saw something past party. The politics of the United States today are red-team, blue-team with little down the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Madison</title>
      <link>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/4_james_madison.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/4_james_madison.html</guid>
      <description>James Madison On James Madison I read Noah Feldman&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Three Lives of James Madison: Genius, Partisan, President&amp;rdquo;.
James Madison reminds me of a mailing list software engineer. He is obsessed with perfecting the constitutional contract. When his beloved document hits real world issues (small states refusing to sign) he is forced to compromise (senate) and back-rationalize his changes.
Obviously, I&amp;rsquo;m not the biggest fan of the president but the author deserves kudos for organizing this biography into the &amp;ldquo;3 lives&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Jefferson</title>
      <link>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/3_thomas_jefferson.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/3_thomas_jefferson.html</guid>
      <description>Thomas Jefferson On Thomas Jefferson I read Catherine Kerrison&amp;rsquo;s tome &amp;ldquo;Jefferson&amp;rsquo;s Daughters: Three Sisters, White and Black, in a Young America&amp;rdquo;.
Kerrison cuts through Jefferson&amp;rsquo;s mythology to show the man how he was in his home and with his family.
What sticks with me the most is when Harriet, daughter of Sally Hemmings (a slave) and Jefferson, is freed (and this is a remarkable moment in itself) as negotiated by Sally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Adams</title>
      <link>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/2_john_adams.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/2_john_adams.html</guid>
      <description>John Adams On John Adams I read David McCullough&amp;rsquo;s tome &amp;ldquo;John Adams&amp;rdquo;.
This is a heavy book. Literally! McCullough&amp;rsquo;s book was so hefty that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t one-hand it on the subway. McCullough does NOT hold back sharing excerpts of Adams&amp;rsquo;s writing. The second president eventually dies July 4th, page 700-something. And I emerge victorious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George Washington</title>
      <link>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/1_george_washington.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://math-ias.github.io/readingthepresidents/1_george_washington.html</guid>
      <description>George Washington On George Washington I read a light and breezy book by Alexis Coe, &amp;ldquo;You Never Forget Your First&amp;rdquo;.
An easy first read to inaugurate my presidential biography project. This chronologically approached Washington&amp;rsquo;s mythos and pointed out fact from fiction. I got the impression the author didn&amp;rsquo;t care for Washington&amp;rsquo;s legendary status and wanted readers to see him more as fellow man. All my heroes are dead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
